Guide to the Stuart Sherman Papers, 1945-2001 (Bulk 1961-2001) MSS.192
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series IX: Video, 63 DVDs
  - Subseries B: Video Recordings - Originals
    - "An Evening of One-Act Plays and 2 Films", HOME for Contemporary Theater and Art, 3/1/87; incl. "Eating", "It is Against the Law...", "The Man in Room 2538", "This House is Mine...", "Endless Meadows...", "The Book and the Window...", "Chatanooga Choo-Choo", "A for Actor", "The Discovery of the Phonograph", 1987; 192.0025A (Box 12, Media 192.0025A)
    - "An Evening of One-Act Plays and 2 Films", 3/1/87, 1987; ID: 192.0120 (Box 16, Media ID: 192.0120)
    - "One-Acts and 2 Films", 2/22/87, 1987; ID: 192.0101 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0101)
    - "They Were Poor, But They Were Honest", Music Hall, 7/18/87, 1987; ID: 192.0023 (Box 12, Media ID: 192.0023)
    - "Mixed Signals" Programs 1+2, Spring 1987; "Discovery of the Phonograph" w/ interview, ID: 192.0103 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0103)
    - "The Yellow Chair" [play], 7/26/87, 1987; ID: 192.0107 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0107)
    - "They Were Poor, But They Were Honest", 7/17/87, 1987; ID: 192.0111 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0111)
    - "School of Jolly Dogs", 12/87, 1987; ID: 192.0112 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0112)
    - "Slant (Concerning Emily Sickinson)", 11/14/87, Hampshire College, 1987; ID: 192.0192 (Box 20, Media ID: 192.0192)
    - "An Evening of Performance and Film" conceived and directed by Stuart Sherman, The Club, La MaMa 6/11/88, 1988; ID: 192.0009 (Box 12, Media ID: 192.0009)
    - "An Evening of Performance and Film", La MaMa, 6/11/88, 1988; ID: 192.0090 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0090)
    - Central Park Performance, 9/11/88, 1988; ID: 192.0106 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0106)
    - "Berlin Tour" [film], 1988; ID: 192.0115 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0115)
      TRT: [00:12:00]
    - Battery Park performance, 9/12/88, 1988; ID: 192.0124 (Box 16, Media ID: 192.0124)
    - "An Evening of Performance and Film", 6/9/88 (Tape 1 of 2), 1988; ID: 192.0130 (Box 16, Media ID: 192.0130)
    - "An Evening of Performance and Film", 6/9/88 (Tape 2 of 2), 1988; ID: 192.0131 (Box 16, Media ID: 192.0131)
    - "Bicycle", Cologne, [1988]; ID: 192.0096 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0096)
    - "Sukiyaki a la Sherman a la Tokyo" and other acts, [1988]; ID: 192.0097 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0097)
    - Dixon's Place 3/10/89, video by Taka Iimura, 1989; ID: 192.0021 (Box 12, Media ID: 192.0021)
    - "Clocktower", 4/22/89, 1989; ID: 192.0050 (Box 13, Media ID: 192.0050)
    - "Clocktower", "Vienna" 4/22/89, 1989; ID: 192.0122 (Box 16, Media ID: 192.0122)
    - "Black-Eyed Susan (Portrait of An Actress)", 1989; 192.0144A (Box 17, Media 192.0144A)
    - "The Fourteenth Spectacle", 8/26/89, 1989; ID: 192.0161 (Box 18, Media ID: 192.0161)
    - "Three Pieces", "Play of Tea", [1989]; ID: 192.0180 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0180)
      Format: Video8
    - "Tea" (A intro), [1989]; ID: 192.0142 (Box 17, Media ID: 192.0142)
    - "Tea" (A), [1989]; ID: 192.0188 (Box 20, Media ID: 192.0188)
    - "Tea" (B), [1989]; ID: 192.0075 (Box 14, Media ID: 192.0075)
    - "Tea" (intro of B+C [?]), [1989]; ID: 192.0127 (Box 16, Media ID: 192.0127)
    - "Tea" (C), [1989]; ID: 192.0145 (Box 17, Media ID: 192.0145)
    - "Tea" (C), [1989]; ID: 192.0181 (Box 20, Media ID: 192.0181)
    - Tech rehearsal for play, late 80s, 198?; ID: 192.0105 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0105)
    - "The Fifteenth Spectacle: Epoche", 6/23/90, 1990; ID: 192.0092 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0092)
    - "The Fifteenth Spectacle" [?], [1990]; ID: 192.0121 (Box 16, Media ID: 192.0121)
    - Artist Talk 9/14/90, 1990; ID: 192.0093 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0093)
    - "Aber Wie Heisst Das Wort For Fahrrad", Kolner Ensemble w/ Stuart, 1990; ID: 192.0113 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0113)
    - Video Mix, Whitney Museum, 11/25/90, 1990; ID: 192.0143 (Box 17, Media ID: 192.0143)
    - "The Sixteenth Spectacle: A Musical", La MaMa, 3/18/91, 1991; ID: 192.0177 (Box 20, Media ID: 192.0177)
    - New Langton, [1991]; ID: 192.0024 (Box 12, Media ID: 192.0024)
    - "The Fifteenth Spectacle", New Langton Arts (SF), [1991]; ID: 192.0108 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0108)
    - Installation, "Video encyc.", New Langton [?], [1991]; ID: 192.0109 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0109)
    - Tom and Stuart, Dixon Place, 10/10/92, 1992; ID: 192.0085 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0085)
    - "New Arts Alive" (BCTV), 9/8/92 (intro. James Carroll), 1992; ID: 192.0116 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0116)
    - Rutgers Tap Teaching Styles, 1993; ID: 192.0028 (Box 12, Media ID: 192.0028)
    - "The Eighteenth Spectacle", 6/17/93, 1993; ID: 192.0043 (Box 13, Media ID: 192.0043)
    - "Cheers!", 5/13/93, 1993; ID: 192.0049 (Box 13, Media ID: 192.0049)
    - "The Eighteenth Spectacle", 6/17/93, 1993; ID: 192.0077 (Box 14, Media ID: 192.0077)
    - "Pixil", Dixon Place, 9/14/93, 1993; ID: 192.0100 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0100)
    - "The Eighteenth Spectacle - Spaghetti Works", 6/12/93, 1993; ID: 192.0175 (Box 20, Media ID: 192.0175)
    - 3/6/1993, ID: 192.0182 (Box 20, Media ID: 192.0182)
    - Karaoke, 3/12/93, 1993; ID: 192.0183 (Box 20, Media ID: 192.0183)
    - "Scaffolding", [1993]; ID: 192.0110 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0110)
    - "A Glass of Fish", [1993]; ID: 192.0045 (Box 13, Media ID: 192.0045)
    - "The Leap" Dailies, [1993]; ID: 192.0047 (Box 13, Media ID: 192.0047)
    - "A Glass of Fish", [1993]; ID: 192.0069 (Box 14, Media ID: 192.0069)
    - Films/Video - "Don't Hang Up, I'm Freezing"; "A Glass of Fish"; "Cheers"; "2 Pixel Videos"; "The Leap"; "Son of Scotty and Stuart", [1993]; ID: 192.0104 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0104)
    - "Liberation (Portrait of Berenice Reynaud)", [1993]; ID: 192.0114 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0114)
    - "Liberation (Portrait of Berenice Reynaud)", [1993]; ID: 192.0132 (Box 16, Media ID: 192.0132)
    - "Son of Scotty and Stuart", [1993]; ID: 192.0134 (Box 16, Media ID: 192.0134)
    - "Cheers!" (#3), Titles for Tape (#1), 2 Pixel Videos (#4): "Black and White" and "Grain", [1993]; ID: 192.0019 (Box 12, Media ID: 192.0019)
    - "Christmas Spectacle", 12/9/94, 1994; ID: 192.0046 (Box 13, Media ID: 192.0046)
    - "X Mas Spectacle", [1994]; ID: 192.0081 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0081)
    - "Perfilmance" at Anthology, 11/5/94, 1994; ID: 192.0074 (Box 14, Media ID: 192.0074)
    - "Perfilmance", [1994]; ID: 192.0012 (Box 12, Media ID: 192.0012)
      TRT: [01:02:00]
    - "Perfilmance", [1994]; ID: 192.0026 (Box 12, Media ID: 192.0026)
    - Dixon Place, 9/10/94, 1994; ID: 192.0088 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0088)
    - Fondation Cartier, Seirees nomades ete 1994, ID: 192.0118 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0118)
      TRT: [00:50:00]
    - Selections - "The Eighteenth Spectacle - The Spaghetti Works", Fond Cartier, Paris, 1994; ID: 192.0123 (Box 16, Media ID: 192.0123)
    - 9/17/1994, ID: 192.0173 (Box 20, Media ID: 192.0173)
    - La MaMa - Musical, 1/10/94, 1994; ID: 192.0176 (Box 20, Media ID: 192.0176)
    - 9/16/1994, ID: 192.0179 (Box 20, Media ID: 192.0179)
    - 5/14/1994, ID: 192.0184 (Box 20, Media ID: 192.0184)
    - 12/10/1994, ID: 192.0190 (Box 20, Media ID: 192.0190)
    - "Pull (A Portrait of David Nunemaker)", 1994; ID: 192.0191 (Box 20, Media ID: 192.0191)
      TRT: 12:04:00
    - "Pull (A Portrait of David Nunemaker)", [1994]; ID: 192.0044 (Box 13, Media ID: 192.0044)
    - "Me and Joe", [1994]; ID: 192.0016 (Box 12, Media ID: 192.0016)
      TRT: [00:04:00]
    - "Holy Bible", "Ah-Choo!", [1994]; ID: 192.0186 (Box 20, Media ID: 192.0186)
    - "Black Eyed Susan", La MaMa - Bill Rice, Stuart Sherman, 2/6/95, 1995; ID: 192.0174 (Box 20, Media ID: 192.0174)
    - Amsterdam - Tape 1, 1995; ID: 192.0178 (Box 20, Media ID: 192.0178)
    - 5/29/1995, ID: 192.0185 (Box 20, Media ID: 192.0185)
    - George and Sherman, 5/30/95, 1995; ID: 192.0187 (Box 20, Media ID: 192.0187)
    - ["Spectacle"] 6/17/97 [?], [1997]; ID: 192.0079 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0079)
    - Tape 3, "Eyes", undated; ID: 192.0052 (Box 13, Media ID: 192.0052)
    - George Ashley; Taxi Dance Performance; [illegible words] "Chekhov", undated; ID: 192.0001 (Box 12, Media ID: 192.0001)
    - N/A, undated; ID: 192.0013 (Box 12, Media ID: 192.0013)
    - "May Project" by Scorpio, undated; ID: 192.0014 (Box 12, Media ID: 192.0014)
    - "Protektion" [?] Kurz Film Festival, undated; ID: 192.0020 (Box 12, Media ID: 192.0020)
    - 8, undated; ID: 192.0022 (Box 12, Media ID: 192.0022)
    - TV Program interview, undated; ID: 192.0037 (Box 13, Media ID: 192.0037)
    - Performance, Sherman #2, undated; ID: 192.0039 (Box 13, Media ID: 192.0039)
    - "…w/ four performers", undated; ID: 192.0040 (Box 13, Media ID: 192.0040)
    - Performance, 3 Mercer, undated; ID: 192.0042 (Box 13, Media ID: 192.0042)
    - MOMA [other illegible titles], undated; ID: 192.0048 (Box 13, Media ID: 192.0048)
    - Tape #1, pre-shoot [unidentified project], undated; ID: 192.0055 (Box 13, Media ID: 192.0055)
    - "Forest Fire", undated; ID: 192.0057 (Box 13, Media ID: 192.0057)
    - Tape #1, "SSB, Nancy Tobin, Stalemate, [illegible subtitles], sneezing", undated; ID: 192.0058 (Box 13, Media ID: 192.0058)
    - Tape #2, pre-shoot, June 12, undated; ID: 192.0059 (Box 13, Media ID: 192.0059)
    - Stuart Sherman segment from KRMA-TV production of "Season Ticket" [interview], undated; ID: 192.0061 (Box 14, Media ID: 192.0061)
    - Tape #2, original material - [illegible subtitles] "music/ bulls/ mouse", undated; ID: 192.0063 (Box 14, Media ID: 192.0063)
    - Stuart [Burbank, Essex ?], undated; ID: 192.0080 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0080)
    - "The Gift of Gab", Artists in Residence, by George Kuchar, undated; ID: 192.0084 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0084)
    - "An Evening with Stuart Sherman and Students", undated; ID: 192.0094 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0094)
    - Stuart Sherman I: Films and Performances, undated; ID: 192.0098 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0098)
    - Stuart Sherman, undated; ID: 192.0099 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0099)
    - K. Kelman's "Uncle Adolf", undated; ID: 192.0119 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0119)
    - Performance selections, undated; ID: 192.0150 (Box 17, Media ID: 192.0150)
    - "Tower", 9/12, undated; ID: 192.0054 (Box 13, Media ID: 192.0054)
    - Stuart Sherman?, undated; ID: 192.0171 (Box 19, Media ID: 192.0171)
    - Subway, undated; ID: 192.0172 (Box 20, Media ID: 192.0172)
    - Selections - Films and Performances, undated; ID: 192.0102 (Box 15, Media ID: 192.0102)
    - Stuart Sherman Performance Tape, undated; ID: 192.0008 (Box 12, Media ID: 192.0008)
    - Stuart Sherman Performance Tape [see 192.0011B for full credit sheet], undated; 192.0011A (Box 12, Media 192.0011A)
  - Subseries C: Video - Paper Material
    - Performance Tape credit sheet, undated (Box 4, Folder 192.0011B)
      Source: 192.0011A
    - "An Evening of On-Act Plays..." at HOME, program/credit sheet, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 192.0025B)
      Source: 192.0025A
    - "Tape 1, Language [?]", shot index notecards, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 192.0133B)
      Source: 192.0133A
    - "Black-Eyed Susan" screening promo card, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 192.0144B)
      Source: 192.0144A
- Series X: Film
  This series contains the film material from the Stuart Sherman Papers.
  This series is arranged into two subseries as follows:
  Subseries A: Film - Access Copies
  Subseries B: Film - Originals
  Researcher access is limited to Subseries A: Film - Access Copies. Repository permission is required for access. Please contact Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2596.
  - Subseries A: Film - Access Copies
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Film materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - Subseries B: Film - Originals
    - Boxing Unedited Footage, Undated; 192.0419 (Reel 192.0419)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Format: 16mm film [Positive], Silent, 700 ft.
    - Stuart Sherman as Robert Beck, Undated (Box 20, Folder ID: 192.0196)
      Format: 8mm
      TRT: [Unknown]
    - Stuart Sherman, Camera - Marianne and Joel, Undated (Box 20, Folder ID: 192.0197)
      Format: Super 8mm
    - [untitled], Undated (Box 20, Folder ID: 192.0214)
- Series XI: Audio
  Scope and Content note
  This series includes audio recordings from the Stuart Sherman Papers.
  This series is arranged into three subseries as follows:
  Subseries A: Audio - Access Copies
  Subseries B: Audio - Originals
  Subseries C: Audio - Works by Others
  Audio recordings by Sherman may be found in Subseries A and B. Commercial recordings owned by Sherman are included in Subseries C.
  Researcher access is limited to Subseries A: Audio - Access Copies. Repository permission is required for access. Please contact Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2596.
  - Subseries A: Audio Recordings - Access Copies
  - Subseries B: Audio Recordings - Originals
    - [untitled], undated (Box 21, Folder ID: 192.0198)
      Format: 1/4" audiotape TRT: [Unknown]
    - 4 Sound Pieces; Telephone, undated (Box 21, Folder ID: 192.0199)
      Format: 1/4" audiotape
    - Telephone, undated (Box 21, Folder ID: 192.0200)
    - 4 Sound Pieces (Doors, Water, "Click", Pinball) + Brecht, undated (Box 21, Folder ID: 192.0201)
    - Tony - Reaction II Flint; Strinberg, 1986 (Box 21, Folder ID: 192.0202)
    - [untitled], undated (Box 21, Folder ID: 192.0203)
    - [untitled], undated (Box 21, Folder ID: 192.0204)
    - 3 Sound Pieces, undated (Box 21, Folder ID: 192.0205)
    - [untitled], undated (Box 21, Folder ID: 192.0206)
    - Atelier de Creation Radiophonique (Rene Farabet), Sherman, undated (Box 21, Folder ID: 192.0207)
    - Radio France - Stuart Sherman, undated (Box 21, Folder ID: 192.0208)
    - [untitled], undated (Box 21, Folder ID: 192.0209)
    - 4 Sound Pieces, undated (Box 21, Folder ID: 192.0210)
      Format: audiocassette
    - Sherman - ACR '93 (Atelier de …), 1993 (Box 21, Folder ID: 192.0211)
    - [untitled], undated (Box 21, Folder ID: 192.0212)
    - [untitled], undated (Box 21, Folder ID: 192.0213)
    - [untitled], undated (Box 20, Folder ID: 192.0214)
  - Subseries C: Audio - Works by Others
    - Ancient Echoes - Chorovaya Akademia, Alexander Sedov (BMG, 1995) (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0224)
      Format: compact disc
      TRT: 00:63:25
    - Satie, The Early Piano Works 2-disc (Philips, 1998) (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0225)
      TRT: 02:22:39
    - Ethel Merman in Annie Get Your Gun cast album (RCA Victor, 1988) (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0226)
      TRT: 00:50:42
    - The Mystery of Santo Domingo de Silos, Gregorian Chant From Spain (Deutsche Grammaphon, 1969) (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0227)
    - Moments of Pleasure single, Kate Bush (EMI, 1993) (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0228)
    - Japanese pop recording (Columbia Japan, 1986) (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0229)
      TRT: 00:70:54
    - Charles Tenet (EMI, 1980) (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0230)
    - "Olde Christmas Caroles", Undated (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0231)
    - Christmas in Choir, The Monastic Choir, The Abbey of the Genesee, Undated (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0232)
    - "Past 3 O'clock", Undated (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0233)
    - "Past 3 O'clock" copy, Undated (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0234)
    - "The Hustle" (loop), Undated (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0235)
    - "Sukiyaki", Undated (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0236)
    - London Cast, High Spirit, Undated (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0237)
    - Virgil Thompson, Mostly About Love, Undated (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0238)
    - Ivor Cutler, "Dandruff", Undated (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0239)
    - Kyu Sakamoto - Sukiyaki, Tankobushi 45 rpm (Capitol Records), Undated (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0240)
      Format: vinyl recording
    - Stefan Brecht, Poems, 33 rpm, 1976 (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0241)
- Series XII: Misc. Media, 28.8 Megabytes in 23 floppy disks.
  This series contains floppy disks.
  Born-digital materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - Digital Files - Stuart Sherman, "Uncle Adolph" (revised); 12/30/00, 2000; 1.44 Megabytes in 1 floppy disk (3.5 inch). (Box Shared Fales 120)
    Format: 3.5" diskette
  - Digital Files - Stuart Sherman, "Me+You (1+2)" [other unidentified works], 1998-2000; 1.44 Megabytes in 1 floppy disk (3.5 inch). (Box Shared Fales 120)
  - Digital Files - Stuart Sherman, "The Stations (requirements)" [and other works], 1999-2000; 1.44 Megabytes in 1 floppy disk (3.5 inch). (Box Shared Fales 120)
  - Digital Files - "thbible", wp versions [?], undated; 1.44 Megabytes in 1 floppy disk (3.5 inch). (Box Shared Fales 120)
  - Digital Files - Books [?], undated; 1.44 Megabytes in 1 floppy disk (3.5 inch). (Box Shared Fales 120)
  - Misc. 5.25" diskettes, undated; 21.6 Megabytes in 18 floppy disks (5.25 inch). (Box Shared Fales 114)
    Format: 5.25" diskettes
- Series XIII: Objects
  This series contains all objects.
  Several objects could not be kept in the collection due to irreparable water damage and/or excessive mold including one Sony Walkman, one bag of multi-colored balloons, two black gloves, two black shoes, and several other articles of clothing.
  - Water gun umbrella ("Disparaguas - Empapate de Alegria"), undated (Box 10, Folder 192.2.0001)
  - Black mask, undated (Box 10, Folder 192.2.0002)
  - Plastic frames (circular glasses), undated (Box 10, Folder 192.2.0003)
  - AIDS ribbon, undated (Box 10, Folder 192.2.0004)
  - Pin of juggler (from Lyppens and Schipper, Amsterdam), undated (Box 10, Folder 192.2.0005)
  - Personal movie viewer with two Stuart Sherman film cartridges (in decorated box), undated (Box 10, Folder 192.2.0006)
- Oversize Series
  This series contains oversize materials from Series IV, VII and includes one performance poster and other oversize artworks.
  This series is arranged into two subseries which describe which original series the oversize materials were withdrawn from. The subseries are labeled as follows:
  Series IV: Performance
  Series VI: Artwork
  - Series IV: Performance
    - Poster - "Stuart Sherman Taal Uilenspiegel" Euro. Performance Tour, 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 137)
  - Series VI: Artworks
    - Drafts - Set/ Stage Design [2 color copies], undated (Box 11, Folder 138)
    - Drafts - Sculpture [6 color copies], 1987, undated (Box 11, Folder 139)
    - Original Drafts - Sculpture [12], 1985-1992 (Box 11, Folder 140)
    - Original Drafts - Sculpture [24], undated (Box 11, Folder 141)
    - Collage works [12], 1995-1996 (Box 11, Folder 142)
    - Framed Artwork - "Rugged Terrain", 1996 (Box 11, Folder 143)
    - Artwork - misc. Paintings, Collage, etc. [6], N/A (Box 11, Folder 144)